Dwight D. Gunning

dwight@dwightgunning.com | http://www.dwightgunning.com | @dwightgunning | +31 6 23 63 83 44

Address: van Tuyll van Serooskerkenweg 73i, 1076JG Amsterdam | Born: 1st July, 1983

Background

Dwight is an Amsterdam based full-stack software engineer. He brings 10+ years experience as a software developer, systems architect and project manager. As a Manager with Accenture he led projects and delivered both packaged and custom solutions to numerous clients in Banking, Telecommunications and Media, and Consumer Products. Since 2013 he has launched and worked as a freelance developer at several startups.

Dwight's expertise is with HTML5/CSS3, Javascript, Python/Django, Web Services (WS-* and ReSTful architectures) as well as message-oriented integration. He also has professional experience writing, deploying and managing systems involving Java, C#/.NET, MySQL, Oracle DB (8-11i), Postgres, MS SQL Server, IBM WebSphere MQ.

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/dwightgunning

Stack Overflow: http://stackoverflow.com/users/263421/dwightgunning

Github: https://github.com/dwightgunning

Work Experience

Software Engineer @ The Cloakroom B.V.

October 2014 - Present

The Cloakroom is an online personal shopping service for men that serves customers in five European markets. As a Software Engineer in a team of four, I coordinate a range of business stakeholders and am involved in developing the company's customer-facing and back-office systems.

Partner & Technology Lead @ Epic Labs B.V.

September 2013 - August 2014

Epic Labs was incorporated by three entrepreneurs to rapidly execute on startup ideas. I led product development and launch of three beta web/SaaS products (HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, Python/Django, Postgres on self-managed Linux VMs.

- Same day meal/grocery delivery: http://groceries.knownly.net
- Online Learning course search: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2G64czIO1jw
- Web-hosting direct from Dropbox: https://www.knownly.net

Founder @ Revirda, Inc.

January 2012 - September 2013

Revirda was a Taxi Driver Intelligence system providing drivers with real-time insight and forecasts of upcoming customer demand. As a technical founder, I architected and developed the suite of applications that delivered the service. This included a rich Javascript powered browser based client, Android (Java) and iOS (Objective C) clients, as well as the Python/Django backend services.

• Website: http://revirda.com

Manager @ Accenture B.V. (The Netherlands)

January 2010 - December 2013

While working at Accenture I performed a diverse range of Subject Matter Expert and Project Management roles:

- Full front-to-back packaged Trading Platform (Murex) for a Dutch bank.
- Performance Monitoring and Diagnostic process definition at a Dutch oil and gas client.
- CRM (Amdocs Clarify), Billing (Comverse) and Oracle DB upgrade (8i to 10g) for a large Dutch Cable TV operator.
- CIO IT Inventory Assessment (Servers, Storage, Networks, End-user computing and Telephony) for a Bank owned Real Estate Investment Management subsidiary.

Consultant @ Accenture PTY LTD (Australia)

January 2005 - December 2009

During my time with Accenture in Australia I had several developer and team lead roles. These were predominantly for the public Government taxation and revenue department. Major highlights were frontend development roles (HTML/CSS/Javascript, ASP.NET/C#, MS SQL SQL Server, IBM WebSphere MQ) and later a Performance Test Manager role delivering a web-portal used by over one million Australian businesses and tax agents.

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology @ Queensland University of Technology

- *Major:* Software Engineering
- Grade Point Average: 5.5 (scale 3 through to 7)

References

Available on request.